(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T13:14:08.133918",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Wah, banyak nih!
Wow, there are so many!
Kita baca loh. Iya nih!
We're reading them! Yeah!
Ikuzo!
Let's go!
Wih, banyak nih! Ah, lucu banget.
Wow, so many! Ah, so cute.
Kita tuh habis jalan-jalan, tau Jepang tuh seru banget nih, ternyata.
We just went traveling, you know Japan is super fun, turns out.
Iya, benar! Iya! Kalian...
Yeah, right! Yeah! You guys...
Kalian sempat lihat apa aja? Makan apa aja?
Did you get to see anything? Eat anything?
Banyaknya banget!
So much!
Oleh-olehnya banyak!
So many souvenirs!
Tadi ketemu siapa? Ketemu Bapak!
Who did we meet earlier? We met Bapak!
Ketemu Bapak, iya!
We met Bapak, yeah!
Tadi ketemu Bapak ya, Goro, tau enggak?
We met Bapak, you know, Goro?
Datang-datang...
He just came along...
So desu ne!
That's right!
Terus ketemu Mbak Ruki sama Mbak Echan.
Then we met Ms. Ruki and Ms. Echan.
Tadi kita tuh apa ya, ngobrol-ngobrol gitu, ditanya gitu kan. "Wah, apa nih yang poin-poin penting dari stream kalian gitu? Charm point kalian gitu?"
Earlier we were chatting and were asked, "What are the key points of your stream? What's your charm point?"
Oh gitu. Makanya, duh, keren deh, kalian nanti tau, ya.
Oh, I see. That's why, it's so cool, you guys will find out later.
Sebelum kita ngomong charm point, perkenalan dulu ya, formalitas-formalitas.
Before we talk charm points, let's do introductions first, just to be formal.
Mulainya mah dari siapa? Siapa dulu deh? Dari tangan kakak?
Who should start first? Whose turn is it? From the big sister?
Oh ya, deh, dari mana? Dari Moona?
Oh yeah, whose turn? From Moona?
Idol agak-agak, rada idol dulu ya. hololive Indonesia ikisei no munahashi no beru...
A slightly idol-like introduction first. hololive Indonesia 1st Gen's Moona Hoshinova...
Next ya.
Next!
Hai hai, Puru Puru Komari Risu! Halo, hololive Indonesia ikisei desu! Ayunda Risuuu!
Hi hi, Puru Puru Komari Risu! Hello, hololive Indonesia 1st Gen! Ayunda Risuuu!
Ohariya! Iofi-san! hololive Indonesia ikisei! Iofi desu. Omishiri okiba wo...
Ohariya! Iofi-san! hololive Indonesia 1st Gen! Iofi here.
Shake-shake! Oh sexy!
"Aku, aku, ini ditayangin apa sih, aku ada titipan buat O-san nih, buat kamu ya, nih."
"I, I, what's being shown here, I have something for O-san, for you, here."
"Kita-kita, kita titipan ini semua aja nih." "Ya udah semuanya aja deh."
"Let's just give all of this." "Alright, let's just give it all."
"Nih O-san, buat kamu ya, Li." "Oke, thank you."
"Here O-san, for you, Li." "Okay, thank you."
"Oh so, before we start, ah, as usual there is #Area15Mini3DLive."
"Jadi buat kalian yang mau screenshot, yang mau komen, bisa di hashtag #Area15Mini3DLive."
"So for those who want to screenshot or comment, use the hashtag #Area15Mini3DLive."
"Gampang guys, tinggal screenshot, easy-easy, just use the hashtag Area 15 Mini 3D Live for the screenshots..."
"It's easy guys, just screenshot, easy peasy, just use the hashtag Area15Mini3DLive for screenshots..."
"Jadi hari ini kita stream apa sih? Kita sebenarnya stream mini, mini, mini, ya mini."
"So what kind of stream is this today? Actually it's a mini, mini, mini, yeah mini stream."
"Iya, mini... 3D mini..."
"Yeah, mini... 3D mini..."
Kita kan mini 3D live ya, guys.
This is a mini 3D live, guys.
Karena namanya tuh mini, ini tuh bukan real konser.
Because it's called mini, this isn't a real concert.
Jadi tuh ini kaya apa ya, versi versi mini and dancing and having fun at the same time.
So it's like... a mini version, dancing and having fun at the same time.
Jadi basically this is just a fun singing stream, karaoke in 3D.
So basically this is just a fun singing stream, karaoke in 3D.
Karaoke in 3D, karaoke di sini.
Karaoke in 3D, karaoke right here.
Sama-sama kan, nyanyi, bakal nge-dance, bakal ber-- enggak kita enggak komedi hari ini.
Together, right? Singing, dancing, we'll-- no, we're not doing comedy today.
Bakal ber-idol ria. Kita tuh bakal menunjukkan apa sih? Menunjukkan apa ya? Potensi-potensi bernyanyi.
We'll be acting like idols. We're going to show... what is it? Our singing potential.
Potensi.
Potential.
Siapa tahu gitu, siapa tahu ya, habis kita menunjukkan yang mini ini, potensi kita nyanyi sama potensi kita dance, kita bisa dapat yang lebih, yang bukan mini.
Who knows, right? After we show this mini one, our singing potential and dancing potential, we can get more than just mini.
Ya, kita dapat yang beneran, itu yang beneran.
Yeah, we can get the real deal, the actual one.
Yang lebih besar, guys, yang lebih besar! Besar! Yang lebih besar, gila.
Something bigger, guys, something bigger! Bigger! Something even bigger, crazy.
Terus nih, kan kita udah 3D nih ya, 3D first generation...
And then, since we're in 3D now, 3D first generation...
Hololive Indonesia 3D, bagaimana kesan dan pesan kalian?
Hololive Indonesia 3D, what are your thoughts and impressions?
Karena kita tuh ya, kita tuh ya biasanya tuh kan cuma apa sih? Cuman kepala doang.
Because usually, we're only... what is it? Just heads.
Sekarang tuh sekarang full body gitu, full body!
Now, now it's full-body, full-body!
How is your impression of your 3D, your own 3D?
Giliran aku? Your turn? Giliran aku?
My turn? Your turn? My turn?
Iya, you first.
Yeah, you first.
Aku pokoknya intinya adalah, dari bisa ngedagang tangan nih, kak, kalau kalau joget biasa kan oke lah, tapi kan kalau lebih pakai apa sih?
For me, the point is, I can move my arms now, sis. If dancing normally, it's fine, but what if you use... what is it?
Ampun nih namanya sign language, kan cuma boleh ini nih, di rumah susah, guys.
Sign language, you can only do this, at home it's hard, guys.
Jadi Yopi mau apa sih? Ngajarin kalian dikit aja, oke.
So Iofi wants to... what is it? Teach you guys a little bit, okay.
Jadi American sign language, thank you like this, put your chin here, thank you.
So American sign language, thank you like this, put your chin here, thank you.
Di dagu ya, guys ya? Dagu ya, guys ya, dagu.
On the chin, right guys? On the chin, right guys, chin.
Itu itu enggak kayak dagu. Chin, here, chin, okay?
That doesn't look like a chin. Chin, here, chin, okay?
Indonesia juga thank-you-nya sama, Indonesia, terima kasih juga di dagu sama.
Indonesia's thank you is the same, Indonesia, thank you is also on the chin, the same.
Iya, dagu.
Yeah, chin.
Cuman, bahasa Jepang beda, di Hongkong itu beda, tapi bahasa Jepang arigatou wa kō desu ne.
But Japanese is different, Hong Kong is different, but in Japanese, arigatou is like this.
Makanya, semete minna ni arigatou yuu ne. Okay?
That's why, at least let me say thank you to everyone, okay?
Arigatou, love you! Yes, muna, giliran mo...
Arigatou, love you! Yes, Muna, your turn...
Muna senang banget, I'm so happy that finally I can show you how I'm dancing and singing at the same time.
I'm so happy that finally I can show you how I'm dancing and singing at the same time.
Because usually when I do the muna-tau, I'm usually, you know, singing and my body is just like want to moving, but you cannot see it and now you can see it, so I'm really happy for that.
Yay, manta... manta...
As for me, as for me, I want to go a little bit to the front, cameraman.
This is hand. This is...
magic hand.
Kita bakal didudukin jagu.
We're going to sit on the chin.
Kita bakal didudukin jagu tadi.
We were going to sit on the chin just now.
Indonesia wa oke, sumimasen, yansuzimasen.
Indonesia is okay, sumimasen, yansuzimasen.
Sumimasen, yansuzimasen.
Nah, ya ku-tutu-de-ne, kita udah, ya kan kita kemarin cuma nyanyi-nyanyi doang. Nih kita mau pose-pose enggak nih?
So, basically, we already... yesterday we were just singing. Are we going to do poses or not?
Oh ya, benar. Pose. Pose mau pose apa nih, teman-teman? What do you want, like, what kind of pose you want to request us?
Oh yeah, right. Pose. What kind of pose do you want, friends? What kind of pose do you want to request us?
Pose, pose mumpung bertiga nih, mumpung bertiga nih.
Pose, since there are three of us, since there are three of us.
Oh, pahanya sangat glowing ya, pahanya glowing sekali.
Oh, your thighs are so glowing, your thighs are glowing so much.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, ya suka deh.
Wow, wow, wow, wow, I love it.
Nggak suka deh, nggak suka.
I don't like it, I don't like it.
Pose apa nih? Pose Jojo? Jojo-jojo gimana nggak tahu.
What pose is this? Jojo pose? Jojo, how, I don't know.
Eto, suki desu.
Apa ya, apa ya, apa? Apa? Mau mau begini guys? Kita baca kok, kita baca.
What is it, what is it? What? Do you want it like this, guys? We read it, we read it.
T-pose, anti-pose.
Oh, anu anu itu, apa sih? Perkenalan senju yang sampai begini loh, coba coba gimana.
Oh, that, what is it? Senju's introduction where it goes like this, try, try how.
Hasshu marine desu. Hasshu marine desu.
Hasshu marine desu.
Ada yang ketagihan lagu gagapnya kamu nih.
Someone is addicted to your stuttering song.
Ada yang ada yang pargoy pargoy itu gimana sih? Pargoy ini kali.
Is there anyone doing pargoy? Like this, right?
Bikin, bikin apa? Apa? Yang gini apa sih, yang gini?
What are we making? What? Like this, what? Like this?
Eh, jongkok bareng kah? Kita kemarin cuma berdua yang... Oh, iya, bertiga, bertiga.
Eh, are we squatting together? Yesterday there were only two... Oh, yeah, three, three.
Sini, sini, sini.
Come here, come here.
Siap.
Ready.
Nggak bisa turun-turun ya, guys, ya.
We can't get back up, guys.
Segini aja.
Just about this much.
Nggak ada beliau ini.
There is no him here.
Beliau ini sungguh...
He really...
Sekali. Ada apa lagi nih? Ada lagi nggak?
Once. What else is there? Anything else?
Ada apa ya, apa ya?
What is it, what is it?
Yang fox? Slay? Slay, slay, slay.
The fox? Slay? Slay, slay, slay.
Eh, nggak mau bat, nggak mau bat, nggak mau pakai, nggak mau pakai.
Eh, I don't want bat, I don't want bat, I don't want to use it.
Yang go...
What's going...
Terus?
Then?
Selanjutnya?
Next?
Waduh, waduh. Ini, ini. Aduh, kita nggak hafal yang begini.
Waduh, waduh. This, this. We don't know this kind of thing.
Apa ya, panjang banget?
What is it, so long?
Iya, apa? Apa? Apa?
Yeah, what? What? What?
Kita harus beli.
We have to buy it.
Ya udah deh. Kita kan udah mau gerak nih, ada game nggak hari ini?
Oh well. We're going to move now, is there a game today?
Harusnya sih ada.
There should be.
Harusnya, harusnya ada ini. Kita kan... Kita kan udah...
There should be. We already... We already...
Udah nunjukkin badan-badan kita nih, sebenarnya kayak gimana. Sayang tuh, sayang banget nggak sih kalau cuma ngobrol doang?
Showed our bodies, what it's really like. Isn't it a waste if we just chat?
Gimana kalau misalnya kita bikin game?
How about we make a game?
Nice. Oke.
Nice. Okay.
Boleh. Squee, la!
Sure. Squee, la!
Iya.
Yeah.
Are you guys ready for the game?
Yes! Yes!
Oke. Gamenya?
Okay, the game?
なりきりトーク対決！ Roleplay Talk Showdown!
[Title: Roleplay Talk Showdown!]
Jeng jeng! Roleplay Talk Showdown!
Siapa nih yang kira-kira aktingnya paling jago?
Who do you think has the best acting here?
Mm, siapa ya? Risu? Biasanya ya, kalau yang sering bikin konten nih.
Mm, who is it? Risu? Usually, the one who often makes content.
Ini, ini, ini, ini yang paling jaga ya, tapi Risu kok.
This, this, this is the most guarded one, but Risu is...
Berbeda. Aduh, ada yang sama tiga.
Different. Oh, there are three the same.
Eh, kalian bisa pakai body language sekarang.
Eh, you can use body language now.
Ya, jadi pada acara kali ini, kita harus mendalami karakter yang diberikan. Oke.
So, for this event, we have to delve into the given character. Okay.
Jadi, kita ngobrolnya tuh sekitar 2 menitan lah, cukup kan ya? Cukup, cukup harusnya.
So, we chat for about 2 minutes, that's enough, right? Enough, should be enough.
Gampang kan ya? Ya, oke.
It's easy, right? Yeah, okay.
Jadi, mulai aja kali ya? Sesi pertama. Jeng jeng! Sesi pertama!
So, let's just start? First session. Jeng jeng! First session!
赤ちゃんで、日本で食べた美味しかったもの / Act like a baby, talk about delicious food you ate in Japan
[Title: Act like a baby, talk about delicious food you ate in Japan]
あのね、あの、あの、お母さん、おねね、え、なんかつらいだよ。おっぱい。ば?
Ah... atsu... um, uh, o-mama, o-nene, is this okay? O-oppai! Ha?
ママ？あ、あの、あい、あい、えっと、あい、いーと、あ、ろっと、おふー、えい、えい、あい、いーと、あ、ろっと、おふー、せいに！あみん、とわす、あ...
Mama? Ah, um... I-I... um, I... etto, I-I ate a lot of food... I ate a lot of food, Seiji! I mean, it was...
あたまごやき？あたっくやきかな？
Atamago yaki? Atakkoyaki kana?
うーん、わかんないよ。でも…あ…でも、おいしい！
Uhn, wakaranai yo. Demo... ah... demo, oishii!
てっきな？あっちんこな？
Tekki na? Atchinko na?
あのね、あっちんここれ…ひとつだちょ、あっちね！
Anu ne, atchinko no... atchinko kore... hitotsu da tyo, atchine!
いちばん、あの、あっちこのたべものね！
Ichiban, ano, atchiko no tabe mono ne!
あっちこ、ぱん！あっちこ、ぱん！
Atchiko, pan! Atchiko, pan!
あっちんこ！あっちんこ！いたいでしゅ、ちゅ！いたいでしゅ！
Atchinko! Atchinko! Itai desu, chu! Itai desu!
いたいでしゅ、ちゅ！いたいでしゅ、ちゅ！
Itai desu, chu! Itai desu, chu!
あれはなんですか？あれはなんでおでんですね？
Are wa nan desu ka? Are wa nan de oden desu ne?
あのね、きのうね…あのきのうじゃなくてさ、あのさ、この数日前に、これね、
Anu ne, kinou ne... anu kinou janakute sa, anu sa, kono suzitsu mae ni, kore ne...
おこんにゃくね、むんにながせたんばけど…むなが、なんか…うん、うん…って言ったんばけど、
O-konnyaku ne, munani nageta nda kedo... muna ga, nanka... um, um... tte ittanda kedo...
よってんだね、けっくちゅきだよ、これが。ええ！
Yotten da ne, kekku chuki da yo, kore ga. Ee!
あっちも、きみのことちゅきだよ！
Atchimo, kimi no koto chuki da yo!
あ、あっちこ…この、この、たけど…あっちきとちゅて…あっちこ！
Ah, atchiko... kono, kono, taked... atchiki tochute... atchiko!
おーでんぐ！あっちこ、おーでんぐ！あっちこ、おいしいよ！
O-odeng! Atchiko, o-odeng! Atchiko, oishii yo!
いたい、いたいでしゅ！どうですよ？なかよちでしゅ？
Itai, itai desu! Dou desu yo? Nakayochi desu?
どうですか？どうですか？どうですか？だってな、これめったちきだなの。
Dou desu ka? Dou desu ka? Dou desu ka? Datte na, kore mětta chuki na no.
ちゅき！めったちゅきちゅきぢなの、これおってん。どうです？
Chuki! Mětta chuki chuki na no, kore o tten. Dou desu?
That's about it. We're babies.
Seru nggak sih? Susah sih kalau ngomong a-a, sulit rasanya.
Emang ngomong apa? Dia tuh udah pro dari tadi-tadi.
Tapi nih, kita soalnya kan banyak yang ke sini, tanya nih ke komentar nih.
Gimana menurut kalian? Kalian paling suka pas bagian mana?
Ada, ada, ada. Siapa nih? Bagian pas cucunya tuh suka.
Mama cucu. Mama cucu. Mama cucu.
まづ次！
First, next!
なんていう？え、 look at you.
What do you think? Eh, look at you.
ねぇ、好きでしょ？
Hey, you like it, right?
オッケー。
Okay.
加藤、アマングガス、アマングガス、アマングガス、や。
Kato, Among Us, Among Us, Among Us, yeah.
アマン。そうだよ。
Aman. That's right.
お、オッケーって言って。
Oh, say "okay."
あと、次ない？次ない？
Also, is there a next? Is there a next?
はぁ。
Hah.
ま、次。
Well, next.
オッケー。次、ゲーム。
Okay. Next, game.
ネクストゲーム。次。
Next game. Next.
お題：ヤンキーで、お互いの3Dの身体で好きなポイント
Act like a street delinquent, talk about favorite parts on your Genmates' 3D bodies
オッケー、みんな準備、準備は？準備！オッケー！スタート！スタート！
Okay, everyone ready, are you ready? Ready! Okay! Start! Start!
げす、げす、さじげす。そう、あい、あい、あい、そう、えっと
Guess, guess, dirty guess. So, I, I, I saw, um...
あのさ、ど、知ってる？レニー、ね？
You know, do, you know? Reine, right?
レニー、彼女のボディ、すっごい！
Reine, her body, it's amazing!
わ、すごーい！ほんとに！めちゃくちゃきれい。
Wow, amazing! Truly! Extremely pretty.
Yang bohay, yeah!
A curvy one, yeah!
Yeah! Tau gak? Tau gak? Tau gak?
Yeah! You know? You know? You know?
Yang bohay lagi, Kaila.
Another curvy one, Kaila.
Yeah! 超、超やばい！超、やばい。先輩、ちょっと、その、パンツ、じゃなくて、パンツの色が、え、超やばい！
Yeah! Super, super crazy! Super, crazy. Senpai, wait, that, pants, I mean, the color of your pants, eh, super crazy!
ってか、やばい。え、どっちが？どっちが？
I mean, crazy. Eh, which one? Which one?
げす、げす。あ、ちょっと待って、そう、私たちいっぱい、私たちいっぱい、ー
Guess, guess. Ah, wait, yeah, we have a lot, we have a lot...
...私たちのほうが、もっとやばい。超やばい！チョー、チョーやばい！
...ours is even crazier. Super crazy! Suuu-per crazy!
だ、だって、一番、きんま、
B-Because, the number one, Kinma...
ぎぶな、ぎぶな、ぎぶな、シェフ、シェフ、キス、ね、ね、ね、ね、ね、
Give na, give na, give na, chef, chef, kiss, ne, ne, ne, ne, ne...
ね、ね、I have one, one of my favorite, her name is Iofi.
Hey, hey, I have one, one of my favorite, her name is Iofi.
ナッパ、エキスパン、エキスパン、エキスパン、彼女の、bottom、ヤバい！
Nappa, expan, expan, expan, her bottom, amazing!
すごい！すごい！すごい！すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing! Amazing! Amazing! Amazing!
え、あ、あ、あ、も、もう、あが。
Eh, ah, ah, ah, m-more, ah.
わ、すごーい！うわ、すごーい！
Wow, amazing! Wow, amazing!
Who's bestie?
すごーい！
Amazing!
ゲット、ギャップ、ハブ、ザ、シークレット。すごーい！
Get, gap, have the secret. Amazing!
なんか、やん、そう来た、こう、なんかすっごい、うちら、うちら、こう、私たち、こう、私たち、こう、私たち、こう、
Like, yan, it came like this, somehow we, we, like this, us, like this, us, like this...
ちょっと待って。もっとさ、もっと、もっと、話そう、話そう、話そう、話そう。
Wait a minute. More, more, let's talk, let's talk, let's talk, let's talk.
ほら、ほら、ほら、ほら、あ、でも、あ、でも、あ、ある、ある、ある、ある、
Look, look, look, look, ah, but, ah, but, ah, there is, there is, there is, there is...
待って、待って、待って、待って。あ！ないの？え、ない、ない、ない。あ、I don't think that... きま、きま。
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Ah! Is there none? Eh, no, no, no. Ah, I don't think that... Kima, kima.
きまい、ま、ま、ま、ま。やった、やった、やった、やった。
Kimai, ma, ma, ma, ma. Yay, yay, yay, yay.
次は？次は何？次は何？次は何？What do you guys think? What do you guys think of the acting?
Next? What's next? What's next? What's next? What do you guys think? What do you guys think of the acting?
いまの、オッケー？すごい。
Was that okay? Amazing.
え、こ、コメント、気にするな、バカ、バカ、バカ、バカ。
Eh, c-, comments, don't worry about them, baka, baka, baka, baka.
誰、誰、誰。
Who, who, who.
え、え、え、え、wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle...
Eh, eh, eh, eh, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle...
オッケー、Thank you! すごい、すごい、そう、Thank you!
Okay, Thank you! Amazing, amazing, so, Thank you!
つぎ、つぎ、次。じゃあ、次、こそ、次こそ、やり、う、which I like、Maybe one more! One more! One more! One more!
Next, next, next. Well, next time, next time for sure, we'll try, which I like, Maybe one more! One more! One more! One more!
お題：みこ先輩風で、今後3人でやりたいこと
Act like Miko-senpai, talk about future plans as HoloID Gen 1
みこ先輩ってどうなの？お前。
What's Miko-senpai like? Hey.
あ、オッケー。レディ？レディ、レディ。レディ？
Ah, okay. Ready? Ready, ready. Ready?
One, two, three, start!
にぇ、にぇ、あ、の、あ、れ、づ、かわいい、にぇ！
Nye, nye, a, no, a, re, zu, kawaii, nye!
にぇ、来年、私は、プライ、にぇ、かわいいです、よ！
Nye, next year, I want to try, nye, it's cute, yo!
来年、私は、私は、とら、ライブ、あ、I can talk, I can talk...
Next year, I, I, want to try, live, ah, I can talk, I can talk...
エリート、エリート、みこ、と、あ！
Elite, elite, Miko, to, ah!
ファッキュウ！ファッキュウ！
Fuck you! Fuck you!
ファッキュウ、is love. え、え、え、え、パ、パ、パ、パ、パ、ユー！
Fuck you is love. Eh, eh, eh, eh, pa, pa, pa, pa, pa, you!
Next year, Oh my god! Next year!
Next year, live concert, ah, HoloID Gen 1, next year...
な、にぇ、にぇ、にぇ、にぇ、にぇ、にぇ。
Na, nye, nye, nye, nye, nye, nye.
ののの、よっぴーもさ、なんか、とってくるね。何、何を、とってくるんだろ。
Nono, Yoppi too, like, brings something back. What, what is she going to bring back?
何がいいんね？
What is good, ne?
フリーダム！
Freedom!
あれ、ねえ、よっぴー、ねえ、え、どら焼き、ねの、あい、どら焼き、ね。
Hey, ne, Yoppi, ne, eh, dorayaki, ne no, I, dorayaki, ne.
来年、we are doing a live 3D... フリーダム！
Next year, we are doing a live 3D... Freedom!
フリーダム！ Let's go, ne!
Freedom! Let's go, ne!
Geng! Geng!
Guys! Guys!
Sebentar, Elite... Elite Moona will come.
Wait, Elite... Elite Moona will come.
Nice and nice-u, not promise!
Nice and nice-u, not promised!
Wah, kayaknya...
Wow, it seems like...
Masih ada satu lagi nih.
There's still one more.
Boleh, gaskan satu lagi.
Sure, let's go with one more.
Let's go! One more! One more! One more!
お題
[Topic]
Using exaggerated reactions, talk about what made you thankful for being in hololive.
Coba ya, cuma-cuma...
Try, ya. Just pretending...
Terima kasih, Hololive!
Thank you, Hololive!
Hololive-nya!
Hololive!
Sebenarnya, sebenarnya Moona tuh...
Actually, actually Moona...
Wah, bahagianya!
Wah, so happy!
You know, talking like this and dancing like this...
We are so happy!
I'm so happy!
Terima kasih, Yagoo!
Thank you, Yagoo!
Eh, help Fubuki sama Bapak!
Eh, help Fubuki and Bapak!
Fubuki sama Bapak! Aaaaaa!
Fubuki and Bapak! Aaaaaa!
Ah, JBP!
Aku undang, aku mau!
I'm invited, I want it!
Thank you, all of you, Bapak! Yes, thank you, Yagoo!
Nah, Miss Guys, bagaimana performa kita tadi?
Now, Miss Guys, how was our performance just now?
Yang mana, guys?
Which one, guys?
What do you guys think, the one that... you know, really good at acting, who has the best acting?
Saya? The best acting?
Me? The best acting?
Yago... Yago sih.
Yag... Yagoo, for sure.
Yagoo sih, dia kan cuma nangis JBP, Fubuki...
Yagoo, for sure, she just cried JBP, Fubuki...
Sepertinya, kayaknya ini... pemenangnya Yagoo ya.
It seems like, looks like... the winner is Yagoo, huh.
Jadi ya udah, kita terima aja. Kalau gitu acting Talk Battle ini dimenangkan oleh Yagoo.
So alright, let's accept it. In that case, this acting Talk Battle is won by Yagoo.
Omedetou! Omedetou!
Congratulations! Congratulations!
Kaget tahu enggak, dia kayak...
Were you shocked, you know, she was like...
Namanya... namanya ini ya, kalau misalnya idol itu harus bisa... the best girl, pasti jago acting.
Her name... her name is this, y'know, if it's an idol, they have to be... the best girl, definitely good at acting.
Benar! The best girl, jago acting. Saya-saya... acting de su, yeah.
Right! The best girl, good at acting. Me-me... acting desu, yeah.
Kalau gitu, kita udah gerak-gerak nih, kita udah gerak-gerak, kita udah ngomong banyak.
In that case, we've been moving around, we've been moving around, we've talked a lot.
Tapi ini masih ada lagi nih. We have something, so we want to prepare. Yes.
But there's still more. We have something, so we want to prepare. Yes.
Don't go anywhere. Eyes on you. Don't forget the hashtag. #Area15Mini3DLive. Don't forget.
Sennin! Sennin! Wah!
Sennin! Sennin! Wow!
kalau kita ke sini
If we're here...
kalau kita tuh ada di kantor, berarti kita tuh udah officially gitu,
if we're at the office, that means we're officially...
officially menjadi anggota... anggota... anggota...
officially become a member... member... member...
Hallo hallo!
Hello, hello!
Ah malas ah, kalau di kantor nanti kita disuruh kerja, aku nggak mau.
Ah, I'm lazy. If we're at the office, we'll be told to work, and I don't want to.
Tapi, nggak apa-apa sih. Kita tuh mau ngapain sih di kantor?
But it's fine. What are we even gonna do at the office?
Nggak usah, nggak usah di kantor, bosan. Ke kamar aja, kamar siapa? Kayak gitu, aku capek.
No need to be at the office, I'm bored. Let's go to a room. Whose room? I'm tired.
Tapi, masih mau di sini? Iya masih, sih.
But do you still want to be here? Yeah, still, though.
Kalau misalnya kamar, gimana ya?
If, for example, you want a room, how is it?
Kayaknya kamar Moona boleh tuh. Oh, boleh, mau? Mau.
Looks like Moona's room is fine. Oh, can I? Want to? Yes.
Cus, let's go! Heya lanta!
Cus, let's go! Hooray!
Wah, akhirnya!
Wah, finally!
Kamarnya bagus banget! Inilah kamar Moona.
The room is so nice! This is Moona's room.
Mana? Oh, nggak ada? Oh ya belum. Nggak ada.
Where? Oh, none? Oh yeah, not yet. None.
Iya masa nggak ada sih? Nggak ada sih, miskin.
Yeah, how could there be none? There's none, poor.
Ganti loh, ya? Haduh, mohon maaf.
Change it, huh? Ah, my apologies.
Iya, yang lebih pagi. Mana tahu di kamar Risu ada. Oh, gitu.
Yeah, earlier one. Who knows, maybe in Risu's room there is. Oh, is that so?
Tapi sebentar dulu, Moona dulu deh. Emang ada apa sih?
Wait first, Moona first. What's actually there?
Jadi ini ada tempat tidur. Ini tempat tidurnya Moona.
So, this is a bed. This is Moona's bed.
Terus di situ tempat... PC lah, PC kita main macam-macam.
And over there is... Come on, PC, we play various things.
I say...
Hey,hey,hey,START:DASH!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
うぶ毛の小鳥たちも いつか空に羽ばたく
Even newborn baby birds will someday soar through the sky,
大きな強い翼で飛ぶ
flying with great, strong wings.
諦めきちゃダメなんだ その日が絶対来る
Don't ever give up, that day will definitely come.
君も感じてるでしょ? 始まりの鼓動
You can feel it too, can't you? The beats of the beginning.
明日へ変われ! 希望に変われ!
Tomorrow, change! Transform into hope!
眩しい光に照らされて変われSTART!!
Transform, illuminated by that brilliant light, START!!
悲しみに閉ざされて 泣くだけの君じゃない
Being closed in by sorrow and just crying — that isn't you.
熱い胸きっと未来を切り開く疼き
With your blazing heart, you can definitely clear the way to the future.
悲しみに閉ざされて 泣くだけじゃつまらない
Being closed in by sorrow and just crying is boring.
きっと 君の チカラ 動かすチカラ
I'm sure your power can set things in motion.
Hey,hey,hey,START:DASH!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
雨上がりの気分で 高まる期待のなか
The mood after the rain amidst growing expectations,
躓いたことさえも 思い出にしよう
even the times when we stumbled, let them become memories.
明日が咲くよ! 希望が咲くよ! 楽しいメロディー口ずさみ咲いたDASH!!
Tomorrow will blossom! Hope will blossom! A fun, hummed melody blossomed DASH!!
喜びを受け入れて 君と僕繋がろう
Grasp the happiness and let's form a connection between us.
迷い道やっと外へ抜け出した疼き
We've finally broken through and found our way.
喜びを受け入れて 君と僕進もうだろ
Grasp the happiness and you and I will push on forward.
それは 遠い 夢の カケラ
Those are a distant dream's fragments...
愛しい カケラ 彼方へと...僕は DASH!!
Precious fragments, towards beyond the border... I'll DASH!!
またひとつ 夢が生まれ...
And again, a dream is born...
Hey,hey,hey,START:DASH!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
悲しみに閉ざされて 泣くだけの君じゃない
Being closed in by sorrow and just crying — that isn't you.
熱い胸きっと未来を切り開く疼き
With your blazing heart, you can definitely clear the way to the future.
I say...
Hey,hey,hey,START:DASH!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
産毛の小鳥たちも
Even newborn baby birds
いつか空に羽ばたく
Will someday soar through the sky
大きな強い翼で飛ぶ
Flying on big, strong wings
諦めちゃダメなんだ
You mustn't give up
その日が絶対来る
That day will definitely come
君も感じてるでしょ
You can feel it too, right?
始まりの鼓動
The pulse of the beginning
明日よ変われ！
O tomorrow, change!
希望に変われ！
Transform into hope!
眩しい光に照らされて変われ START!!
Illuminated by brilliant light, START!!
Hey,hey,hey,START:DASH!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
見つめ合って恋をして
Staring at each other, falling in love,
無我夢中で追いかけて
chasing in a frenzy,
だけどもっと知りたくて メラメラしてる
But wanting to know more, burning up.
願うほど謎が増え 想うほど熱になる
The more you wish, the more mysteries increase,
だからもっと飛び込むの 未知の世界
So I'll dive further into an unknown world.
恋とか夢とか 誰でも信じるけど
Everyone believes in love and dreams,
そこそこ攻めなきゃつまらないよ
But it's boring if you don't push it a bit.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Desperate love, the forbidden borderline,
難易度Gでも 全部壊してみせる
Even with difficulty G, I'll break it all down.
キリキリ舞 さらにGへと
A dizzying spin, towards even more G,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
Consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable,
イッちまうかもね
I might just go.
戯れ合った友達と
With friends joking around,
求め合ったあの人と
And that person we sought,
また会える日のために ギラギラしてる
Shining brightly for the sake of meeting again,
光るほど影ができ 燃えるほどhighになる
The more it shines, shadows form, the more it burns,
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Desperate love, the forbidden borderline,
難易度Gでも 全部壊してみせる
Even with difficulty G, I'll break it all down.
キリキリ舞 さらにGへと
A dizzying spin, towards even more G,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能 イッちまうかもね
Consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable, I might just go.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Desperate love, the forbidden borderline,
何の時代も 全てを壊して見せる
In any era, I'll break everything down.
ギリギリマインド さらに自由へと
Desperate mind, towards even more freedom,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
Consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable,
イッちまうかもね
I might just go.
叫び合った友達と 求め合ったあの人と
With friends we shouted with, and that person we sought,
また会える日のために キラキラしてる
Shining brightly for the sake of meeting again,
光るほど影はでき 燃えるほどhighになる
The more it shines, shadows form, the more it burns,
走るほど見えてくる 危ないライブ
The more you run, the dangerous live becomes visible,
自由も平和も 望めば生まれるけど
Freedom and peace are born if you wish for them,
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Desperate love, the forbidden borderline,
燃え尽きながら まだ輝いてみせる
While burning out, I'll still shine on,
ギリギリマインド あなたのために 未来のために
Desperate mind, for you, for the future,
何度砕け散っても 愛することで生まれ変わる
No matter how many times I shatter, I am reborn by loving,
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Desperate love, the forbidden borderline,
難易度Gでも 全部壊してみせる
Even with difficulty G, I'll break it all down.
キリキリ舞 さらにGへと
A dizzying spin, towards even more G,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能 イッちまうかもね
Consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable, I might just go.
限界点なら 塗り替えていい
If it's the limit, it's okay to rewrite it,
乗り越えて 破壊と再生から 私が出来る
Overcoming it, from destruction and regeneration, I can do it.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Desperate love, the forbidden borderline,
何の時代も 全てを壊して見せる
In any era, I'll break everything down.
キリキリ舞 全てを壊して見せる
A dizzying spin, I'll break everything down.
ギリギリマインド さらなる自由へと
Desperate mind, towards even more freedom,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能 イッちまうかもね
Consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable, I might just go.
見つめ合って恋をして
Staring at each other, falling in love,
無我夢中で追いかけて
chasing in a frenzy.
だけどもっと知りたくて
But wanting to know more,
メラメラしてる
we're burning up.
願うほど謎が増え
The more we wish, the more mysteries grow,
想うほど熱になる
the more we think, the hotter it gets.
だからもっと飛び込むの
So we'll dive even deeper
未開の世界
into an unexplored world.
Dan-dan ココロ Dan-dan アツアク
Step by step, hearts heating up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
we'll make all our dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, moving forward, bursting out,
未来をしっかり見て!
keep your eyes fixed on the future!
未来をしっかり見て！
Keep your eyes fixed on the future!
進め まだまだ Let's go!!
Move ahead, still more, let's go!!
進め ほらほら Let's go!!
Move ahead, come on, let's go!!
大事なことはなんだっけ？
What was that important thing again?
小さな努力が明日を作るんだ
Small efforts create tomorrow.
いまを愛してぶつかってみよう！
Let's love the present and collide head-on!
そんな勢いでずっと一生懸命なんだ！
With that kind of momentum, always giving our all!
もっと近くで語り合いたいな
I want to talk more closely with you.
逢いたい君とどこまで走ろうか
How far shall we run together, the you I want to see?
果てまで走ればいいさ
We can just run all the way to the edge.
限界知らない All right?
No knowing limits, all right?
これからの Wonderful Rush
Our Wonderful Rush from here on,
みんな幸せになるため
so everyone can find happiness.
新しい世界 探しに行こうよ
Let's go search for a brand new world!
迷ったら Wonderful Rush
If you get lost, Wonderful Rush,
僕は輝きを信じて
I believe in the radiance.
遥か遠くの虹だけど…そう、きっとつかんで!
It's a distant rainbow, but... yes, we'll surely grasp it!
Dan-dan ココロ Dan-dan アツアク
Step by step, hearts heating up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
we'll make all our dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, moving forward, bursting out,
未来をしっかり見て!
keep your eyes fixed on the future!
人生気分で上下左右
With a life-of-the-party mood, up, down, left, right,
運命ときどき急展開
destiny sometimes takes sudden turns.
最低↓最高↑最大↑最新↑
Lowest down, highest up, maximum, newest,
Let's go! 遠くに Super jump!!
Let's go! A super jump far away!!
なんだろね不思議だよ
I wonder why, it's so mysterious.
楽しいと感じるこの時は
When we feel this joy,
瞬間のようで永遠のようだね
it feels like a fleeting moment yet eternal.
一緒に跳ぼう Dan-da-Dan-Dan!
Let's jump together, dan-da-dan-dan!
大事だよ (なんだっけ?)
It's important (what was it?)
小さな努力 (そうだった!)
Small efforts (that's right!)
いまが好きで (愛なんだ?)
Loving the present (is it love?)
ぶつかるんだ (そうなのさ!)
Colliding head-on (that's right!)
勢いよくね (大胆に?)
With full momentum (boldly?)
一生懸命 (そうだった!)
Giving our all (that's right!)
勢いつけて (大胆に?)
Building up momentum (boldly?)
一生懸命だ!
We're giving our all!
もっと気持ちを分かち合いたくて
Wanting to share our feelings even more,
隣にいる君 いつでも一緒だから
you're right beside me, always together,
(いるから)いっしょがいいね
(because you're here) being together is great
(心配いらない All right?)
(no need to worry, all right?)
はじまりの Wonderful Stage
The beginning of the Wonderful Stage,
みんな次の場所立つんだ
everyone stands at the next place.
めぐり逢う季節 新鮮な景色
Seasons we meet in, fresh scenery,
胸はずむ Wonderful Stage
hearts fluttering on the Wonderful Stage.
僕が目指すのはきれいな 遥か遠くの虹だから…さあ、出発だよ!
What I aim for is a beautiful, distant rainbow... come on, let's set off!
Wonderful... Wao!
どうしようか? Dreams come true
What should we do? Dreams come true.
当然 Let's go! Three, two, one, zero!!
Naturally, let's go! Three, two, one, zero!!
Hi hi, Super jump! Oh yeah, Super jump!!
Life is wonder まだまだLet's go!!
Life is wonder, still more, let's go!!
Hi hi, Super jump! Oh yeah, Super jump!!
Life is wonder Wonderful Rush
もっと近くで語り合いたいな
I want to talk more closely with you,
逢いたい君とどこまで走ろうか
how far shall we run together, the you I want to see?
(果てまで)走ればいいさ
(all the way to the edge) we can just run
(限界それに? No thank you, OK!)
(limit to that? No thank you, OK!)
Oh yeah (心配いらない All right!!)
Oh yeah (no need to worry, all right!!)
これからの Wonderful Rush
Our Wonderful Rush from here on,
みんな幸せになるため
so everyone can find happiness.
新しい世界 探しに行こうよ
Let's go search for a brand new world!
迷ったら Wonderful Rush
If you get lost, Wonderful Rush,
僕は輝きを信じて
I believe in the radiance.
遥か遠くの虹だけど…いつか手にする
It's a distant rainbow, but... someday we'll hold it in our hands.
Wonderful Stage
みんな次の場所立つんだ
everyone stands at the next place.
めぐり逢う季節 新鮮な景色
Seasons we meet in, fresh scenery,
胸はずむ Wonderful Stage
hearts fluttering on the Wonderful Stage.
僕が目指すのはきれいな 遥か遠くの虹だから…さあ、出発だよ!
What I aim for is a beautiful, distant rainbow... come on, let's set off!
Dan-dan ココロ Dan-dan アツアク
Step by step, hearts heating up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
we'll make all our dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, moving forward, bursting out,
未来をしっかり見て!
keep your eyes fixed on the future!
Dan-dan ココロ Dan-dan アツアク
Step by step, hearts heating up,
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
we'll make all our dreams come true!
Dan-dan ススム Dan-dan ハジケル
Step by step, moving forward, bursting out,
未来をしっかり見て!
keep your eyes fixed on the future!
ダン ダン ココロ ダン ダン アツアク
Dan-dan heart, dan-dan getting hotter
夢いっぱい叶えてみせる
I'll make all my dreams come true
ダン ダン ススム ダン ダン ハジケる
Dan-dan moving on, dan-dan bursting out
未来をしっかりと見て！
Look firmly toward the future!
ハイハイ 進め！ まだまだ Let's go!!
Hi hi, move on! Still, let's go!!
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, future dreams
大きな希望 忘れない
Grand hopes I'll never forget
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
出会いは ふとした瞬間
Our meeting was in a sudden moment
帰り道の交差点で
At the intersection on the way home
声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
You called out to me, "Let's go home together"
僕は 照れくさそうに カバンで顔を隠しながら
I hid my face shyly behind my school bag
本当は とても とても 嬉しかったよ
When the truth is, I was so, so happy
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, fireworks blooming so pretty in the night sky, feeling a bit bittersweet
あぁ 風が時間とともに 流れる
Ah, the wind flows along with time
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険もいろいろしたね
We were so happy and had fun going on various adventures
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base, just the two of us
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, future dreams
大きな希望 忘れない
Grand hopes I'll never forget
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知っていたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile is so heartbreaking
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
あぁ 夏休みも あと少しで 終わっちゃうから
Ah, summer vacation will end soon
あぁ 太陽と月 仲良くして
Ah, the sun and moon get along so well
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩もいろいろしたね
We were so sad and lonely, we had all sorts of fights
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base, just the two of us
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知っていたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile is so heartbreaking
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
突然の転校で どうしようもなく
With a sudden transfer, there was nothing we could do
手紙かくよ 電話もするよ
I'll write letters, I'll make calls
忘れないでね ぼくのことを
Don't ever forget about me
いつまでも 二人の 基地の中
Inside our secret base, forever
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
Talking endlessly at the end of summer with you
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
Watching the sunset, then gazing at the stars
君の頬を流れた涙は ずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears streaming down your cheeks
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll surely never forget you waving your hand big until the end
だから こうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に
So like this, inside a dream, forever and ever
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, future dreams
大きな希望 忘れない
Grand hopes I'll never forget
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知っていたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile is so heartbreaking
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
Menyedihkan sekali, Moona terharu.
How sad, Moona is touched.
Tahu enggak, tahu enggak? Liriknya tadi Natsu Yasumi owari, apa gitu?
You know what? Earlier the lyrics were like
"Natsu Yasumi owari", or something?
Obāchan-ka?
Obāchan-ka! Iya ini sudah mau habis Natsu Yasumianya.
"Obāchan-ka!" Yeah, Natsu Yasumi
is almost over.
Natsu Yasumianya! Natsu Yasumi!
Natsu Yasumi! Natsu Yasumi!
Eh guys, mau duduk enggak? Capek.
Hey guys, want to sit down? I'm tired.
Iya nih duduk. Yuk yuk yuk. Duduk duduk duduk.
Yeah, let's sit. Come on, come on.
Sit, sit, sit.
Jadi gimana, teman? Bagaimana sudah bernyanyi berapa lagu tadi?
So how is it, friends? How many songs
did we sing earlier?
Satu, dua, empat ya? Empat, empat.
One, two, four, right? Four, four.
Langsung tuh, enggak ada break. Langsung empat live, teman-teman.
Right away, no break. Four live songs
straight, friends.
Moona capek, langsung tek-tek-tek-tek. Yang satu masuk-keluar, Ma-Suhook, Pa-Eko, hahahaha.
Moona is tired, right away tap-tap-tap.
One goes in and out, Ma-Suhook, Pa-Eko...
Kalian-kalian milih lagu-lagu ini kenapa sih?
Why did you guys choose
these songs anyway?
Ee kalau tadi tuh yang pertama banget ya, ee lagu apa sih? Start Dash, itu karena kita bertiga kan ya?
Um, if the first one, um, what song was it?
Start Dash, because there are three of us?
Bertiga.
Three.
Pioneer!
Oh my God, emang kita pioneer? Iya, ya? Masih tahu enggak sih?
Oh my God, are we really pioneers? Yeah?
Do you still know?
Risu bela-belain belajar dance deh. Eh guys!
Risu went out of her way
to learn dancing. Hey guys!
Kalian harus tahu, jadi kalian kalau nyadar ya, di showcase-nya Risu dia enggak ada ngebuka dance? Iya.
You guys need to know, if you notice,
in Risu's showcase she didn't dance? Yeah.
Iya, pas ini kita, Risu kamu enggak mau terus ngedance deh.
This time, Risu, you didn't want
to keep dancing.
Benar loh, benar loh, Risu ya ini Yopi mo- terima mo-seriusan dikit ya.
That's right, Risu, Yopi, take this
a little seriously, okay?
Kalian kalau mau nangis, nangis saja semua. Jadi yang enggak biasa ngedance itu...
If you guys want to cry, just cry.
So the one who's not used to dancing...
dance bertiga-tiga itu Risu kan? Nah awalnya kayak kita, Risu, tadinya kuis-kuis dia awalnya nyanyi cuman kayak nyanyi doang.
in a trio is Risu, right? At first
Risu just sang like singing.
Bisa kayak gini. Ternyata, ternyata bagaimana kalau kita ngedance? Wow.
Can be like this. Turns out,
what if we dance? Wow.
Risu kayak, hah, terus Moona bilang,
Risu's like, hah, then Moona says...
Kamu-kamu masuk ke dunia entertainment idol, Hololive, saatnya kamu belajar dance.
You entered the idol entertainment world,
Hololive, it's time to learn to dance.
Iya, kayak gitu. Awalnya, awalnya Risu enggak bisa banget guys, sekarang udah bisa, kalian lihat kan tadi, hebat.
Yeah, like that. At first, Risu couldn't
do it at all, now she can, you saw it.
Tadi tuh last minute kita sempat-sempat latihan juga gitu. Kita sempat latihan. Kita latihan lihatnya di Yago tahu enggak tadi?
Earlier, last minute we even had time
to practice. We practiced with Yago!
Yago, kata Yago, "Gamba ttene." Gambai-gambai. Moona bilang, "Yago, Zennaku! Idol!" Zennaku! Idol! Zennaku! Idol!
Yago said, "Gamba ttene." Moona said,
"Yago, Zennaku! Idol!" Zennaku! Idol!
Rusuh ya kata-kata ya, kaya power ya. Ah, ya, kita-kita udah, udah selesai. Kita jumpa lagi.
Chaotic, you know, full of power.
Ah, yes, we're done. See you again.
Kita tuh enggak cuma ngedol nih, kita enggak cuma ngedol, kita ada pengumuman.
We're not just idling, we're not just idling,
we have an announcement.
Oh, ada pengumuman apa nih? Pengumuman Moona has a little bit announcement.
Oh, what announcement?
Moona has a little bit announcement.
Siap? Siap, penasaran? Oke. Tiga, dua, satu, ini dia!
Ready? Ready, curious? Okay.
Three, two, one, here it is!
Wah, apa nih? Wah, lucu banget, ada acrylic stand. Ada aku juga.
Wow, what is this? Wow, so cute,
there's an acrylic stand. There's me too.
Acrylic stand, bestie! Kelix stand-nya itu ya, kalau enggak salah ya, bukan yang kecil.
Acrylic stand, bestie! The acrylic stand
is, if I'm not mistaken, not the small one.
Oh yang gede? Iya. Kita, kita, kita ges, ges, ges, gimana, gimana? Size body approximately 220-235mm, base / approximately 80-80mm.
Oh the big one? Yeah. Size body
approximately 220-235mm, base 80-80mm.
Ya, pokoknya ini yang gede. Yang tinggi, yang tinggi. Kayak gini guys.
Yeah, basically this is the big one.
The tall one, the tall one. Like this guys.
Ekornya tuh, ekor pinggangnya tuh enggak bisa dinaikin. Ayo, pinggangmu! Pinggangmu!
Her tail, her waist tail can't be raised.
Come on, your waist! Your waist!
Jadi, this is a 3D acrylic stand, special with our 3D model and with our pose.
So, this is a 3D acrylic stand,
special with our 3D model and our pose.
Because usually, uh uh when we only have 2D models, we don't really have any dynamic pose.
Because usually, when we only have 2D models,
we don't really have any dynamic poses.
For the first time... Pose, man. Try to pose. Pose.
For the first time... Pose, man.
Try to pose. Pose.
Aduh gila keren banget, gas.
Man, this is so cool, let's go.
Eh, tapi... gak cuma ini, loh.
Hey, but... that's not all, you know.
Oh, ada lagi!
Oh, there's more!
Not just this, we have another one.
What is it?
Apa gini?
Like this?
Tada!
Aduh bestie, bestie,
Oh, besties, besties,
teman-teman, ada other three special items!
guys, there are other three special items!
Yes.
Everyone's Best Friends, Risusaurus!
And My Bestfriend Moomo!
Yes!
And Kyawaii Chiyopi!
Let's go, let's go, ini dia!
Let's go, let's go, here it is!
Moo chest!
Ini kecilnya segini loh.
This is how small it is, you know.
Nah jadi size aslinya tuh seperti ini, so, approx the real size.
So the actual size is like this, so, approx the real size.
You can see the size on the screen, right?
So, there's a reason why we showed this on our 3D showcase, yes.
Because we want to let you know how cute our...
Yeah, Risusaurus! And this is Chiyopi, this is Yopi.
No, this is Yopi! This is Yopi! This is Yopi!
Aduh ini tuh siapa?
Oh, who is this?
Eh, this is Chiyopi, this is Yopi!
Chiyopi is small, Yopi is big.
Yopi.
Lala, aduhian.
Lala, oh man.
Don't forget to buy it, it's on sale starting from September 20.
Yes, check out!
September 20.
Please buy it because it's so cute.
It's so cute, you know.
If you also, you know, this is like a version of plain one, you can add black glasses as well.
You can buy the glasses by yourself.
And also this Risusaurus, it's actually Risu in dinosaur pajamas, yes.
So this is basically mini Risu, just like Chiyopi.
Yeah, yes, this is Chiyopi, big Yopi, Chiyopi.
Risu, Risusaurus, Moomo!
Biar dekat di hati, guys.
So it's close to your heart, guys.
Iya, aduh hari ini Yopi enggak stream, gitu kan.
Yeah, today Yopi isn't streaming, you know.
Ada ini, waduh dicium-ciumin, ngomong, ngomong, wangi-wangi.
There's this, oh, kissed, talking, talking, it smells nice.
So yeah, if you're really interested, no, actually, you need to buy it.
We've waited for 17 months to actually release this, so please buy it, make it sold out, yes.
Make it sold out, there will also be available, you can check on the link, usually it's in Hololive Indonesia Twitter.
Yes, you can check in Waxart and also in the description of the videos gonna be added in the description later.
Yes, please buy it, buy five for your family, okay? Buy four or more, I mean.
Who love your wife, who love your kids, buy. Sayang anak, sayang istri, beli.
Who love your wife, who love your kids, buy. Love your child, love your wife, buy.
Tu, wa, ga, fuu!
Betul Lamy, aduh udah disayang seperti anak sendiri lihat tuh.
Right Lamy, man, they're loved like our own children, look at that.
Anak mama. Terus ya, terus.
Mama's children. And then yeah, then.
Apalagi nih? Kita kan udah promosi ya, dan nih udah ngelawak.
What else? We've promoted, right, and made jokes.
Terus uh ni uh...
And then uh...
Kita kita kita ngomongnya agak berat-berat dulu kali ya.
We should talk about some heavy stuff first, I guess.
Oh ya udah, ini mau disimpan dulu enggak? Apanya? Ini.
Oh alright, do you want to save this first? What? This.
Oh ya udah, simpan.
Oh alright, save it.
Udah, ini terima kasih, terima kasih, thank you so much.
Alright, thank you so much, thank you so much.
Aduh, ada yang nangis-nangis ya, bentar aku belum.
Ah, someone is crying, wait, I haven't yet.
Aduh, aku tuh di-diriku sendiri tuh aku juga mau nangis, kalian sih.
Man, I myself felt like crying too, because of you guys.
Ini tuh ya, teman-teman, karena ini tuh adalah...
You know, guys, because this is...
Karena ini tuh live kita bertiga gitu.
Because this is our stream together of the three of us.
Jadi apa ya? Terima kasih atas dukungannya sejauh ini.
So, what can I say? Thank you for the support so far.
Kita sudah 2 tahun lebih ya, teman-teman.
We've been together for over 2 years, guys.
Jadi tuh semoga ini adalah apa ya, awal untuk Hololive Indonesia
So hopefully this is like, the beginning for Hololive Indonesia
supaya bisa lebih berkembang lagi, teman-teman.
to grow even more, guys.
Ingat, ini cuman mini 3D live, tapi semoga kita bisa mendapatkan live yang benar-benar live.
Remember, this is just a mini 3D live, but hopefully we can get a truly live stream.
Terus setelah kita, kita juga berharap untuk gen-gen yang selanjutnya nih kita tunggu di panggung yang selama ini kita impikan ya, teman-teman.
And after us, we also hope for the next generations that we've been dreaming of seeing on stage, guys.
Jadi semangat!
So stay spirited!
Ditinunggu gen selanjutnya, oke?
Look forward to the next gen, okay?
Terus dari kalian nih aduh, jangan mau nangis.
And from you guys, oh man, don't cry.
Dan karena setiap dari Hololive Indonesia enggak cuma satu gen aja ya, tapi semua membernya itu kan selalu...
And because every member of Hololive Indonesia isn't just one generation, but all members always...
dengarkan suara mereka yang terbaik dari diri mereka sendiri,
Listen to their best voice from themselves,
Karena itu...
Because of that...
aku tunggu, Moona tunggu untuk gens selanjutnya
I've been waiting, Moona's waiting for the next gen
dan juga sebagai penutup, mari kita
and also as a closing, let's
menyanyikan lagu untuk Hololive dari Hololive Indonesia untuk semua orang.
sing a song for Hololive from Hololive Indonesia for everyone.
Ya? Pada siap?
Right? Are you ready?
Siap?
Ready?
Aduh sebentar, gimana nih? Siap belum nih?
Oh wait, how is it? Are you ready?
Komentarnya lagi, komentarnya lagi. Iya komentarnya lagi nangis.
The comments again, the comments again. Yeah, the comments are crying again.
Wah Hololive Indonesia bikin kalian nangis lagi, kita... aku pengen
Wow, Hololive Indonesia made you guys cry again, we... I want a
call and response dong biar kaya idol-idol.
call and response so it's like real idols.
Apa-apa? Gimana-gimana?
What? How?
Kayak gini, kayak kamu gambar Risu, nanti yang tiang komentarnya... gambar Risu! Gitu.
Like this, like you draw Risu, then the comments... draw Risu! Like that.
Oke oke oke, dari siapa? Dari Risu dulu?
Okay, okay, okay. From who? From Risu first?
Dari Risu nih aku.
From Risu here, me.
Oke, oke kita ya?
Okay, okay, us?
Call and response?
Call and response, oke? Kalian panggil sih?
Call and response, okay? You guys call?
Call and response, okay? You guys say puru-puru, you say "Gamba-Risu!" Okay?
Okay, from now.
One, two, three.
Puru-puru! Gamba-Risu!
Yee, gila! Hore!
Yay, crazy! Yay!
Selanjutnya, Moona ya?
Next is Moona, right?
Iya, iya.
Yes, yes.
Kalau Moona bilang "Moon-Moon", kalian bilang "Moona-dayo!", oke?
When Moona says "Moon-Moon", you guys say "Moona-dayo!", okay?
Oke.
Okay.
Moon-Moon! Moona-dayo!
Yee! Hebat!
Yay! Awesome!
Aduh, terakhir ya? Iofi silakan.
Ah, last one, right? Iofi, please.
Aduh sebentar.
Oh wait a minute.
Euphoria! Hololive!
Jadi teman-teman panggung yang sudah kita impimpikan sudah menanti.
So, friends, the stage we've been dreaming of is waiting for us.
You guys ready?
Yes.
I am ready.
id:entity voices!
Dengarkanlah suaraku
Hear out my voice
id:entity
Berdiri di tengah terangnya kilau cahaya
Standing in the middle of the bright spotlight
Ohayou! Konbanwa! Kami serukan kepada dunia
Good morning! Good evening! To the world we shout out
Mengudara 'tuk hari ini
Going live for today
Bagian dari diri yang manakah
Which part of myself
'Ku tak dapat pernah memutuskan
Could I never quite decide
Lalu suatu hari pesan-pesan berdatangan
And then one day, messages came flooding in
Kata-kata perih membuatku kehilangan arah
Hurtful words made me lose my way
Senyuman di balik layar sanggupkah untuk 'kupertahankan?
Will I be able to keep the smile hidden behind the screen?
Tak pernah ingin kecewakan siapapun di luar sana
Never wanting to disappoint anyone out there
Namun di saat banyaknya suara manakah yang 'ku harus dengar?
But among all these voices, which one should I listen to?
Mencoba mendengarkan suara di dalam hati
Trying to listen to the voice inside my heart
Inilah diri yang ingin 'ku selalu tunjukkan
This is the self I always want to show
Berbagai suara yang berpadu dan menjadi satu id:entity
Various voices blending and becoming one id:entity
Hari-hari berlalu dan sekarang 'ku di sini
Days go by and now I'm here
Berdiri di tepi panggung ini menyambut dunia
Standing at the edge of this stage greeting the world
Tetapi 'ku tak sendiri bersama lainnya sekarang
But I'm not alone anymore, together with others now
Seakan seperti keluarga bersatu dalam perbedaan
Almost like a family united in differences
Namun di saat banyaknya perbedaan dapatkah harmoni tercipta?
But when there are so many differences, can harmony be created?
Bergandengan tangan berjuang raih mimpi bersama
Holding hands, striving to reach dreams together
Semua bersorak dengan suara gempita
Everyone cheering with loud, joyful voices
Menyebarkan kebahagiaan di mana pun itu, bergemalah
Spreading happiness wherever it may be, let it echo
Panggung yang lebih besar kini menunggu
A bigger stage is now waiting
Waktunya telah tiba tanpa adanya ragu
The time has come without any hesitation
Dengan semua warna suara menjadi harmoni sebenarnya
With all the colors of our voices becoming the true harmony
dengarkanlah suaraku
Hear out my voice
id:entity
berdiri di tengah terangnya kilau cahaya
Standing in the middle of the bright spotlight
ohayou! konbanwa!
Good morning! Good evening!
otsukaresama deshita!
Good work today!
ohayou! konbanwa!
Good morning! Good evening!
kita 'kan jumpa lagi
We will surely meet again